<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<vocabs xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
	<vocab>
		<origin>Able leader</origin>
		<speech>N.</speech>
		<meaning>聰明能幹的領袖</meaning>
		<sentence>Requiring a benchmark for education, however, will discriminate against able leaders who have been denied schooling because of gender, poverty or caste, and who have nevertheless worked to educate themselves.</sentence>
	</vocab>
	<vocab>
		<origin>Bias</origin>
		<speech>N.</speech>
		<meaning>偏見</meaning>
		<sentence>In research published in the Quarterly paper of Economics in 2009 and in Science magazine in 2012, my colleagues and I showed that living in a village that had elected a female leader caused villagers to report lower bias against female leaders.</sentence>
	</vocab>
	<vocab>
		<origin>Castes</origin>
		<speech>N.</speech>
		<meaning>（印度社會的）種姓制度</meaning>
		<sentence>The demographic makeup of those elected is also more diverse, in large part a result of the constitutional requirement that a certain fraction of council head positions, or Pradhans, be reserved for women, lower castes and tribal groups.</sentence>
	</vocab>
	<vocab>
		<origin>Catalyse</origin>
		<speech>V.</speech>
		<meaning>催化</meaning>
		<sentence>Village councils headed by women can catalyze change.</sentence>
	</vocab>
	<vocab>
		<origin>Competent</origin>
		<speech>Adj.</speech>
		<meaning>有能力的</meaning>
		<sentence>There are better ways of ensuring that elected politicians are competent and effective.</sentence>
	</vocab>
	<vocab>
		<origin>Consistent</origin>
		<speech>N.</speech>
		<meaning>一貫的（Positive）</meaning>
		<sentence>In surveys, including ones we conducted in Rajasthan in 2010, voters consistently report a strong preference for educated leaders.</sentence>
	</vocab>
	<vocab>
		<origin>Constitutional requirement</origin>
		<speech>N.</speech>
		<meaning>憲法允許的要求</meaning>
		<sentence>The demographic makeup of those elected is also more diverse, in large part a result of the constitutional requirement that a certain fraction of council head positions, or Pradhans, be reserved for women, lower castes and tribal groups.</sentence>
	</vocab>
	<vocab>
		<origin>De facto</origin>
		<speech>Adj. , Adv.</speech>
		<meaning>（可不被法律接受但）實際存在</meaning>
		<sentence>A de facto handing over of local political control to the better off will not help solve Rajasthan’s gap between rich and poor, or stark gender inequality.</sentence>
	</vocab>
	<vocab>
		<origin>Disempower</origin>
		<speech>V.</speech>
		<meaning>使減少信心</meaning>
		<sentence> The effect, however, will be to disempower the historically disadvantaged — women and the poor. </sentence>
	</vocab>
	<vocab>
		<origin>Diverse</origin>
		<speech>Adj.</speech>
		<meaning>Various and different</meaning>
		<sentence>The demographic makeup of those elected is also more diverse, in large part a result of the constitutional requirement that a certain fraction of council head positions, or Pradhans, be reserved for women, lower castes and tribal groups.</sentence>
	</vocab>
	<vocab>
		<origin>Domestic chore</origin>
		<speech>N.</speech>
		<meaning>家務</meaning>
		<sentence>By creating empowered female role models, it led villagers to state more equal aspirations for their teenage sons and daughters and to reduce their daughters’ domestic chores and increase their schooling.</sentence>
	</vocab>
	<vocab>
		<origin>Fertility</origin>
		<speech>N.</speech>
		<meaning>生殖力</meaning>
		<sentence>Back in 1992, it became the first state to require that candidates for village council positions have no more than two children — a rule that particularly hurts lower castes and tribal groups, where fertility rates are highest.</sentence>
	</vocab>
	<vocab>
		<origin>Financial stake</origin>
		<speech>N.</speech>
		<meaning>股份</meaning>
		<sentence>Over the last decade, as India has expanded its social safety net and increased investments in rural infrastructure, the financial stakes of village elections have risen.</sentence>
	</vocab>
	<vocab>
		<origin>Fraction</origin>
		<speech>N.</speech>
		<meaning>分數；小部分</meaning>
		<sentence>The demographic makeup of those elected is also more diverse, in large part a result of the constitutional requirement that a certain fraction of council head positions, or Pradhans, be reserved for women, lower castes and tribal groups.</sentence>
	</vocab>
	<vocab>
		<origin>Incidence</origin>
		<speech>N.</speech>
		<meaning>發生率</meaning>
		<sentence>A recent paper found that these limits increased the incidence of sex-selective abortions, and a qualitative study in Northern India from 2005 reported that men got around the law by disowning later-born children and occasionally deserting their wives.</sentence>
	</vocab>
	<vocab>
		<origin>Negotiate</origin>
		<speech>V.</speech>
		<meaning>（就…）談判</meaning>
		<sentence>The politicians behind the education requirement have argued that less educated leaders failed to be effective administrators and were less able to resist corruption and negotiate with district officials.</sentence>
	</vocab>
	<vocab>
		<origin>Ordinance</origin>
		<speech>N.</speech>
		<meaning>法令</meaning>
		<sentence>Earlier in December, the governor issued another ordinance requiring candidates to have a functional toilet, effectively eliminating many of the poor.</sentence>
	</vocab>
	<vocab>
		<origin>Rationale</origin>
		<speech>N.</speech>
		<meaning>根本原因</meaning>
		<sentence>The rationale was to create more effective and less corrupt administrations.</sentence>
	</vocab>
	<vocab>
		<origin>Rural</origin>
		<speech>Adj.</speech>
		<meaning>鄉村的 （Countryside）</meaning>
		<sentence>Over the last decade, as India has expanded its social safety net and increased investments in rural infrastructure, the financial stakes of village elections have risen.</sentence>
	</vocab>
	<vocab>
		<origin>Skew</origin>
		<speech>Adj.</speech>
		<meaning>使歪斜</meaning>
		<sentence>And it has some of the most skewed child sex ratios, as a result of sex-selective abortion and reduced parental investment in daughters.</sentence>
	</vocab>
	<vocab>
		<origin>Stark</origin>
		<speech>Adj</speech>
		<meaning>毫無修飾的；嚴重的；極端的</meaning>
		<sentence>A de facto handing over of local political control to the better off will not help solve Rajasthan’s gap between rich and poor, or stark gender inequality.</sentence>
	</vocab>
	<vocab>
		<origin>Surpass</origin>
		<speech>V.</speech>
		<meaning>超過</meaning>
		<sentence>Elections are held every five years, and voter turnout regularly surpasses that in state and national elections.</sentence>
	</vocab>
	<vocab>
		<origin>The fray</origin>
		<speech>N.</speech>
		<meaning>激戰</meaning>
		<sentence>The campaign caused more literate villagers to enter the fray as candidates, and these candidates gained a higher fraction of the vote. </sentence>
	</vocab>
	<vocab>
		<origin>Upward of</origin>
		<speech>Prep.</speech>
		<meaning>More than</meaning>
		<sentence>Upward of half the state’s adult male population and three-quarters of its adult female population have been disqualified from running in the elections that begin this week.</sentence>
	</vocab>
	<vocab>
		<origin>Voter turnout</origin>
		<speech>N.</speech>
		<meaning>投票人數</meaning>
		<sentence>Elections are held every five years, and voter turnout regularly surpasses that in state and national elections.</sentence>
	</vocab>
</vocabs>